Of course there will be times when you really just don't know what you want the best person to ask is
当然，有时候你真的不知道你想要最好的人问什么
your waiter or your waitress right there the first person that you should ask because they've seen so
你的服务员或你的女服务员是你应该问的第一个人，因为他们已经看到了
many people order.
很多人订购。
They know what people like and they've probably tried everything on the menu.
他们知道人们喜欢什么，他们可能已经尝试过菜单上的所有内容。
Probably right.
大概是对的。
So they're the first person you should go to.
所以他们是你应该去的第一个人。
How can you ask them for their advice.
你怎么能向他们征求意见。
You really have no idea.
你真的不知道。
Everything looks so good.
一切看起来都那么好。
You can say that everything on the menu looks so good.
你可以说菜单上的所有东西看起来都很好。
I'm having trouble deciding I'm having trouble deciding what to get.
我很难决定我很难决定要买什么。
Everything looks so great.
一切看起来都那么棒。
Now they might ask you a specific question.
现在他们可能会问你一个具体的问题。
Do you like fish.
你喜欢鱼吗。
Are you looking for something vegetarian.
你在找素食吗？
Do you prefer chicken or beef chicken or beef.
你喜欢鸡肉还是牛肉鸡肉还是牛肉。
Do you prefer chicken or beef.
你喜欢鸡肉还是牛肉。
And then based on that maybe she can make a recommendation or you really have no idea.
然后基于此，也许她可以提出建议，或者您真的不知道。
Just tell me what would you suggest.
告诉我你有什么建议。
What would you suggest or what's popular here.
你会建议什么或这里流行什么。
What's popular on the menu.
菜单上流行的东西。
What's hot on the menu or sometimes what's popular here what do people often order.
菜单上的热门菜或有时这里流行的菜人们经常点的菜。
What do people people often order.
人们经常订购什么。
The I hate tuna is really popular here.
我讨厌金枪鱼在这里很受欢迎。
He I think it's a guy that I could be wrong.
他我认为这是一个我可能是错的人。
He tuna the ahi tuna is really popular here.
He tuna ahi 金枪鱼在这里很受欢迎。
That's a very popular item on the menu item popular item on the menu.
那是菜单上非常受欢迎的项目 item 菜单上的受欢迎的项目。
That sounds really good.
这听起来真的很好。
I love tuna.
我喜欢金枪鱼。
I'll have that.
我会的。
So the waitress has recommended something and I have taken her recommendation because one I love tuna
所以女服务员推荐了一些东西，我接受了她的推荐，因为我喜欢金枪鱼
and two I have no idea.
还有两个我不知道。
So she must know what's really good in this restaurant.
所以她一定知道这家餐厅有什么好吃的。
Sometimes I even say that.
有时我什至会这么说。
Well what's your favorite thing.
那么你最喜欢的东西是什么。
What do you like.
你喜欢什么。
Sometimes I will ask that question too.
有时我也会问这个问题。
We can also say what do you recommend.
我们也可以说你有什么建议。
What are the specials today.
今天有什么特别的。
This best shows today.
这是今天最好的节目。
Many restaurants have something that they call a special each day that could be a certain type of fish
许多餐馆每天都有他们称之为特别的东西，可能是某种鱼
or maybe a specific dish.
或者可能是一个特定的菜。
Right.
正确的。
A dish.
一道菜。
And it depends on the day.
这取决于日子。
Monday Tuesday Wednesday.
星期一星期二星期三。
Maybe they have different specials.
也许他们有不同的特色。
And the waiter or waitress might tell you about those.
服务员或女服务员可能会告诉你这些。
Oh today we're doing a special on we're doing a special on tacos type of Mexican food.
哦，今天我们正在做一个特别的关于我们正在做一个关于墨西哥卷饼类型的特别食物。
Our special tuna tacos tuna tacos.
我们特制的金枪鱼炸玉米饼 金枪鱼炸玉米饼。
OK sounds good.
好的听起来不错。
Sounds good I'll try that.
听起来不错，我会试试的。
Those are the specials.
这些是特价商品。
So don't worry if you can't decide at a restaurant you can ask for advice you can use these expressions
所以不要担心如果你不能决定在餐厅你可以寻求建议你可以使用这些表达
these ways to ask.
这些方法来问。
And there are others of course you can mix these around as well.
当然还有其他的，你也可以混合使用。